Yeah. So glad you guys came downstairs
uh to hear about this talk. Uh quick
raise of hands. Who's building with AI?
Who's like building touching LMS,
managing agent loops, etc. Cool. Who's
using u AI coding tools or coding
agents? So most of us. Cool. So a lot of
this will be familiar for us. So, uh, I
figured I' I have some slides. I also
have a demo and I basically just going
to free form to see depending on the
audience go back and forth. So, uh, this
is your time as well. Um, so hopefully
it's going to be super valuable. U, so
first slide. Uh, I'm actually I came in
from San Francisco. Uh, I live in
Oakland specifically and we have a train
system. But, uh, the one thing I just
want to point out is like this is a New
York City in the US is like the best
subway system of all country. Uh, I know
there's like some quirks around it, but
uh I'm always impressed on my ability to
navigate and get around the city. Uh,
despite never living here, uh, that's
been here quite a bit of time. So, uh,
the blue arrow is actually where I'm
staying and the red arrow is where we
are right now. And what I love to do on
the plane ride over is always try to
figure out, okay, how am I going to
commute? Uh, I used to I have like three
metro cards, so it turns out like my
metro cards are dead after December. Um,
but I just love being on the metro. Uh,
taking buses when I'm in the uh in
Manhattan and uh so this is my commute
and I also like walking a ton, but
walking from Barclays down to here is
just not a great walk. Uh especially
with this weather. Uh so I decided to
use a train. So on the right is my uh my
phone. I use Citymapper. That's that's
my uh sort of like go-to whenever I'm in
a different city. And this is my commute
specifically. Uh I want to point out
this because that one line is the BMT.
Uh it's actually a historical line as
well. Um Brooklyn had over overground
train line. Um I never knew what BMT
stand stood for. Uh so Brooklyn Marine
Oh, I was it trans? No.
Oh man. I I had the acronym. Doesn't
matter what it is because it's a
sandwich. Um and I only know BMT from
the sandwich at Subway, which why I'm
wearing my Subway hat. Uh, but this is
the line I took this morning. So, six
stops. So, you have like 1 2 3 4 5 6.
You get off at 36th Street, you're good.
Um, got on Decb. But there's also this
other option which is only one stop and
I always I know about express trains.
Anybody take the train in? Anybody
local? Cool. And anybody local that took
the train? So, this is all I'm I'm not
educating you on anything at this point,
but it'll correlate. So, uh, this is the
end. And I was like, "Oh, I accidentally
got on the end on the way over to the
workshops yesterday." I was like quite
impressed because it's one stop from
Barclays to here. And I'm like, "Man,
that's that's amazing. Like I can only
just get one function and I can have
like a oneshot experience to get here."
Does that make sense to what we're
getting here? Uh, cool. So, I'm Boggy.
Uh, I This is me on the internet. Um,
uh, it's awkward to say this, but you
can Google me. Um, I spent a lot of time
at GitHub doing developer advocacy. I
was an early employee at Netifi, worked
at a company called continue now uh
doing DevX there. Also ran another
company for 2 years that I sold at the
Linux Foundation. I'm just really really
into open source and I joined continue
because they're open- source first
company. So we're truly a dev tool that
does AI. Uh and that's the one thing I
like about continue. So continue we ship
faster continuous AI and I won't get
actually I'll show you a demo um of
continuous AI and what we're thinking
about like what this is. Uh but we
actually didn't start here. This is like
what we're sort of like shipping in the
last two months. Uh we'll have a big
announcement on December 1st around
this. But what we started was custom
agents. So like we were one of the first
to get VS Code working with OAMA uh
coding agent experience. So use your
local models run it. Um it's like hit or
miss. Anybody using local models uh for
writing code for for anything really?
Yeah, it's like hit or miss at this
point. Like we're in a word of like a a
valley for local models at this moment.
Like we've got some like Kimmy just came
out not too long ago. Um GPTOS OSS
120B like that exists. GLM exists but
Quinn exist Quinn 3 coder as well. Uh
which is a great model. Um but there's
always some quirks on like I was
actually it's like a weird flex. I was
just hanging out with bite dance last
night. Um this is recorded. By the time
this comes out they'll have an
announcement. But what I'm getting at is
uh I I get to hang out with all these
model providers and like local models
and like all these um like experiences,
but the challenge is when you get the
experience to work for that model, what
we have and I I was going to have a
slide for this, but uh I I call our our
users, our open source users
freeloaders, uh because they're always
load testing the free models uh to try
to get as as good as the the paid
foundational models. So to get Quad
Sonet 45 experience, like you're not
getting there. I'm just going to let I
spent all day in Discord. I'm I'm
answering issues. I'm like, I'm sorry,
dude, but it's just not happening. Like,
if you want Sonnet, pay for Sonnet. If
you want local models, fine-tune eval
yourself to like almost okay. Um, but
that's just kind of where we are today.
Like, we we can wait for another um um
model training or foundational models to
give us and gift us more open source
models, but that's that's the game that
we're in right now. So uh at continue we
sort of broken down our custom
configurations for agents and like these
these concepts of like models rules and
tools. Uh so models is a given. You
choose your your model local or hosted
rules. Uh we spent a lot of time over
the summer making rules better just
similar like cursor rules but inside of
continue. And then tools is where I'll
spend most of my time talking to about
which the title of this talk was about
virtual tool calling which um I'll be
honest like I pitched the same talk that
Robert's pitching right now upstairs
about agent like management and they're
like oh we have that talk but did you
want to do a local model thing I was
like okay yeah I could do that. Uh so
virtual tool calling is something that
was it's it's always been a challenge
and I think a lot of us have solved this
like early days and I want to go to the
demo so I I cut out a bunch of slides
but early days we had function to
calling from OpenAI it was great because
you can call a function and it would do
some stuff and then we had the evolution
of that where you could then um have
agentic function tool calling where you
can like it can reason and respond um
and the way we're able to do this with
continue because we have so quent three
code is actually a big issue for us
because it's just it's a great model but
it doesn't do it the way everyone else
does it. So we have to like intervene
and give you the experience you expect.
So like when you're freeloading uh
it's like a not a term I want to use
publicly but I'm here in public saying
it out loud but like when you're
freeloading to try to get the best
experience like a co-pilot or like a
cursor experience uh we've got to
intervene by basically injecting XML for
tool calling. Uh so the way we've done
this is uh I like the term virtual tool
calling and we called that for a while
but it really is system message tools uh
because we're this injecting this in the
system message the tool with the XML. So
that's what's highlighted there in red.
Um
I realize this is red and green so
apologies for accessibility. Um but we
do have a docs as well that explains all
these concepts. And I felt I honestly I
was kind of rolling the dice. I didn't
know how many people would show up here.
So I'm like, let me just tell you docs
exist and then let me show you how it
works. Um, so this is a live URL. OSSFY
is I'm very proud of owning that domain.
Uh, as I mentioned, I love o open
source. Uh, but I built a calculator and
um
hopefully it's easy to remember because
I'm going to move away from that. Uh, so
I built a calculator and it looks like
and it looks like oh where's my Oh, you
know what I did? Okay, we'll just pull
it up. So it looks like this. Pretty
basic. Uh I can probably oop quiet quad.
Um so like you can just do like 7 8 9.
Oh, it doesn't work. Calculator is a
little broken. So like the idea here is
like we should be able to work in this
calculator. And I actually that's not
intentional. I should clear the cache
and restart because [snorts] it should
not be broken.
Okay. Oh, cool. Cool. Yeah. So we got
like this 67.
Cool. So like the calculator works. I'm
just like proving a point. I've also
added like some cool little tools that I
vibe coded last night. So if I do like
does that. So like I have a bunch of
like Easter eggs, but it was just like
last night I was like cool. I need like
a demo. I had another demo, but I wanted
something new because vibe coding is
like it's dope. I gotta be like
I gonna make a joke about that, but uh
I'm gonna just move on. All right. So So
I have this calculator app and then I
have the code here. U so the repo itself
is uh that URL that I showed you is
actually going to go to the actually
does anybody go to that? Does it go to
the repo or the GitHub repo?
>> I don't think the calculator.
>> Yeah, I think it might have went to the
GitHub repo. Um no, actually it goes
here. Sorry, there's a GitHub repo which
I I had mentioned meant to uh show so
apologies but it's AI native dev calc.
Um so that's the the repo. Um but I
wanted to share that in case anybody
really cared to like do this themselves.
Um so this is VS Code and in VS Code I
have u the read me and then I basically
have the working calculator. Uh my
background is like front-end developer
for some reason. Like I I worked at a
job that I interviewed in Go and they
told me do React and then I turned in
their front end dev like 10 years ago.
So uh I didn't have a lot of experience
there. Uh it's essentially just
JavaScript in HTML. It's super simple.
Um but I found with the calculator um it
was it was quite broken. Uh so if I do
like 888 and I hit percent, it doesn't
actually add the permit sent. adds the
decimal which is not how calculators
work and I'll prove that um real quick
which I'll just do like 888 and then I'd
expect a percent right so we have a bug
in our code so uh what I'm going to do
and I apologies on the uh the swiping
foo but uh I'm looking at my current
file and I'll probably add uh the other
file which is a JavaScript oh all the
files oh appjs yeah so add the appjs and
just say hey the the percent is broken
is broken and oh you know I thought I
had a percent's broken and go ahead and
fix that. Oh did I I had to hold it. Uh
fix it please.
I told myself I'd use whisper flow and
not type the entire time. Um but we'll
see how it goes. So I have this
specifically in agent mode and this is
like our virtual tool calling. It's
going to work. This is actually not this
is going to work no matter what because
it's open AI model. Uh but I'm going to
try a different one real quick. Just
just you have a t% is broken. I think
they give you
>> Yeah, that's totally fine because uh
it's an agent. They know exactly what I
mean. They always know your intent and
will never hallucinate. Um
>> just like give it.
>> No, no. We we we want to oneshot
everything and force agent to do our
will. Um and then hopefully they don't
come back and hurt us. Um but I'm going
to switch to plan mode because I don't
want to I don't actually want it to
write any code. Uh, I just want to show
you it's going to write. So, plane mode,
I think, is pretty common across most
coding agents. It's just going to be
read only tool access. And I'm doing
that mainly because I don't want to have
to clean up a bunch of code. Uh, but the
idea here is that it's going to think uh
and it's it's going to one shot. It's
actually not hitting any tools. So, this
is a this is not a good example.
Um, but I have a different example. Let
me try using a different model. Let me
try using a harder model. Um, and this
is this is kind of where like the
virtual tool calling comes. So, I know
where is my oh, Gemma. So, Gemma is
actually one of my favorite models to to
leverage. Uh, it's a very small model,
but because I'm running on a 32 gig
machine, uh, and I do a lot of work on a
train. I I didn't mention this. Well, I
I run a train uh in in SF called the
BART, so the Bay Area Rapid Transit. And
I spend a lot of time because I get on
where I can get a seat and I'll just
like start working. Um, but what I like
to do is I go offline uh quite a bit.
So, uh, what's cool about this is like
it is going to run local. Um, and it
actually won't run local because I need
to go to my local config and then switch
to not Quinn 3 because that will melt my
machine. Um, but yeah, looks like the
Oh, wait. Hold on. I said I was going to
do this so let me try it again. Uh,
looks like the percent is broken. Can
you fix that? The percent button.
Oh, whisper flow won't work um with that
on. Yeah. Anyway, I'll just type it.
So, the cool cool thing about like
continue and everything running local is
I can still get my virtual tool calling
and all thing on my machine. So, it's
still going to run. Um, unfortunately,
Whisper Flow won't work.
Cool. So, it did. um it's going to call
the search tool. So this wanted to prove
that it's it's going to hit a tool. Um
and the way Gemma um the 4B model
specifically doesn't have tool calling
built in by default. Uh so it's just
like it was shipped pre agentic flows.
So one of the proof point it works this
is how it works. Um but my talk doesn't
really just talk about calculators. It's
it's all about the uh portability of
these tool calling as well. So, um, the
goal for the the like earlier this year,
I think maybe last summer is like when
we had a breakthrough of agents. Uh, I
think the first one I saw was like crew
AI had figured out how to like make
agents talk to agents as well. Uh, and
then shortly after that all the coding
agents started shipping agents. I think
cursor might have been first. I'm sorry
if I don't have all the the the dates
correct. Um, but it's it's basically go
think, process, reason, and then like
present the result. Uh, and I thought
that was amazing. But the challenge of
like working on a platform like continue
and again I do apologize folks at the
back. I was going to change the colors
of this but I'll let you know what 1 2 3
4 5 is. We have fragmentation of tool
calling. Uh, so the way tools work in
one model is not the way they work in
other models. Uh, and it's painful to
manage. So like we're just at a point
where at continue we're just like hey
here's our recommended models and if you
want other models contribute. And that's
kind of what been our our our statement
for the past three months. Uh but
stateless, so stateless is going to be
like your quad code. It's not storing
state. It's like doing stuff really
fast, really quick. Uh anybody use quad
code or have experience using that? I
think a lot of us had at this point have
touched it or or tried it out. Uh and
it's a great experience because and
there's also codeex as well, low
friction. Um autonomous is uh very
similar to open hands. Uh so it is like
as if a a human was going to go through
and do some specific steps. uh and
specifically store some state. Um
and then compiler uh Ry actually was
talking about compiler agents uh
previously but cursor this is kind of
how they they interact. Uh and it's
funny every time we talk to like was I
don't know if this is actually funny but
it's funny to me uh when we talk to
different foundational model providers
or even just general model providers for
even open models they always ask us this
question of like how do you handle tool
calling? like well we we've got this
thing we just like inject the XML and we
try to lean into the stateless realm. Uh
but there are some situations where we
do have to add state for like certain
situations and I'll get into that as in
a moment. Uh and then the talk after uh
I I probably should check with George
because I don't want to put him in the
wrong headsp space but like uh I believe
like what George is doing with Stackpack
which is be the talk right after this um
is going to fall within uh these realms
here like domain specific but also
planning and routing as well for
specifically DevOps pipelines. So I
mentioned this is like pretty much every
weekend for me I get like 10 of these
issues opened up in the continue repo of
like hey I've got a random model you've
never heard of it doesn't work. I was
like, "Well, I never heard of it. It
doesn't work because we just haven't got
that far." Um, so it's constantly always
like regurgitating our our docs and
pointing people about this. This is
basically the headsp space I was in a
couple months ago when I was like making
this talk was I'm answering this
question all the time. Let me just
create a talk for this and then
hopefully I'll make a blog post for this
and maybe a series on how like this
works in detail. Um, but yeah, but this
is the answer. It's it's virtual tool
calling. Um, so when I think about like
that experience and what else you can do
with that cuz like we built this
flexibility within our our platform to
like manage local models, uh, manage
hosted models, manage models from random
providers who we haven't heard of. Um,
you like the portability of being able
to say I want to be able to oneshot
myself from Barlays to this location.
Um, we have frameworks around this. So
like that's another implementation which
I don't have a live demo for. Um, but
MCP is like being able to like call an
MCP based on whatever model you're
leveraging is also challenging because
MCP is all being like we're about a year
into this space, but it's also all over
the place. Um, so if you want to build a
coding agent, like man, it's a lot of
work. Um, just come work for continue.
Um, so what we've been doing is we've
been experimenting with like what I call
legacy dev tools. And when I say legacy
is like preai. Uh, so a lot of our our
our favorite tools like Century, who's a
big fan of Century? you guys in there
every day and like, man, this is my job.
I can't believe this is it. Errors.
No. Okay. Well, that's that's basically
my life pre uh pre AI. It's like, man, I
don't know what I'm doing with these
errors. Unless it's broken, I'm just not
going to go look in there. Um and then
when I something broken, like I'm going
to go search through there and like what
a amazing agentic workflow is like to
triage and debug this. So um at continue
we've been experiment like experimenting
with like how you can leverage whatever
model you want specifically with
whatever MCP you want uh to be able to
solve problems that are like scoped and
spec specifically to that situation. Um
and that's what we've been doing with um
continuous AI. So it is like being able
to take centure errors. I was talking to
Cloudflare a couple weeks ago and they
said like in the last 7 days they had
well this is ironic because they had an
issue. Uh but in the last seven days
they had like 60 million sentry errors
for like one one task and I was like
that makes sense because you guys went
down because of a SQL error but uh I say
that now because I read the article this
morning on what happened the postmortem.
Uh man timing. Uh so what we've been
doing is we've been experimenting with
continue. So I showed you specifically
like the VS Code IDE. We have Jet Brains
as well. But then we built this thing
which is our CLI. And again, there's a
lot of CLIs out there like choose your
own adventure at this point. Uh but we
wanted to do is like build bespoke
situations within the CLI that are ready
and pluggable to go solve century errors
and go solve sneak vulnerabilities and
go solve PR review. Uh so what this is
is basically our take for custom agents
uh for situations for you to like go lay
deploy and uh sort of set and forget. So
this was an experiment we did over the
summer around July is like build a CLI.
We're using ink which is the same thing
quad code is built on top of. Um and
then the next step is like it's the same
demo but I'm going to go into um the web
interface real quick. Uh let me turn my
internet back on.
You asked me if I had a internet demo
and then I forced myself into fouring
myself uh by turning that off to prove a
point. Uh so we'll give it a second to
come back. Um,
all right.
Oh, I might have cursed myself forever.
Oh, here it is. Cool. Um, yeah. So,
basically what I'm getting at is like we
at continue, we've been experimenting
with this, so I guess I'll just look at
my own. But the idea is what if you
could take your sentry errors and uh
Sentry has a specific tool called Seir.
Uh, and Seir is like their agentic flow
to basically get you to like code it up.
Uh, which is funny. I think it's funny
because that's what the the buttons
called inside of Century. It's it says
code it up. Um it's I I was using
OpenAI's uh chat dbt and it like it came
back with or no it was codeex and it was
like heck yeah. Um and I was like wow
that's awkward. Um cool. Um let me just
move on to like writing code. Uh but
anyway coded ups is what they call it.
Uh but the idea here is I can actually
click this solve button. So this is um
in the last 5 days I got seven of these
events. Uh the idea is I can kick off a
task that's specified and like bespoke
custom agent that failed to start. So I
just saw the failure message. So I'll
check out the century error and what
happened to that century. But the idea
is that I can go see um that task in
this list if it didn't work. Uh and then
specifically say okay these century
errors are being solved uh on at my whim
uh specifically. Uh and this is what it
would look like. So I ended up um in the
calculator uh the clear button it I
wanted it to specifically have a if you
hit clear you should see all clear. Um
we all know calculators right we it's
been a while uh some of us are new out
of school some of us have not been
school a while but um basically what I'm
getting is I wanted to like just prompt
up a really quick calculator um fix for
that button. I prompted it using this
little task flow here uh and get kicked
it off. So very similar like my sentry
experience except the prompts already
built in to like fix this error based on
this sentry take. Um so when I was
talking about models rules and tools I
can have that experience of like model
rules for century and specifically the
MCP for that. So uh I do like this
because it does give you some extra
steps to like choose your own event
share to the next thing. Uh but wanted
to share like this is like I believe
where most of where your coding agents
are going. Um I think the the GMO RO
who's the CEO of Verscell tweeted
yesterday no two days ago of a survey of
if you're doing coding agents like are
you using synchronous are you doing
async uh are you doing background and I
think background was 5% of like the
respondents so like it's it's whoever
follows him and that's that's a response
but uh I think we're still pretty early
in this so uh just wanted to share that
little demo uh this is sort of the a the
continuous AI workflow we're sort of
thinking about where we have like a
trigger which is your century error uh
and then the outcome which is fix this
centry error uh and the idea there is
that you can have a continuous loop so
you have an angentic cycle of like
sentry error is solved um but you sort
of do eval
solution so we've with sear you can do
high medium low usually the low ones you
can oneshot uh and have like that sort
of one one stop train stop uh but
majority of them are going to be
multi-step like let's just break this
down create issues uh so the one thing I
did want to point out is that like when
I kick off a task
Um, if I kick off a task, uh, I can
choose my own agent. So instead of like
opening up PR the fix, I have that same
experience where I can just create a
GitHub issue. Uh, and I actually created
a couple issues before this. Um, so like
backspace doesn't work. So continue
opens up a plan that I can just kick
off. And so yeah, so that's sort of like
the portable tool calling and how I'm
sort of like closing the loop on this.
Um, another example we have in our MCP
cookbooks is Post Hog. I don't look at
post hog like why uh I'm not a product
manager but there's a lot of good
session data that I can take digest into
text uh and then respond with like
either issue or PR the fix. So if your
onboarding is broken uh and you only
like convert 25%. Ask Post Hogs MTP and
continue as agent or pick your whatever
agent like you can do whatever uh and
then generate a bunch of plans to like
go test and and distribute that. And the
thing that works the best is like go set
up a new tracking uh metric for post hog
to track to see if it works after the
fact. And I've been pushing a lot of
engineers that continue to like do that
last step because I think a lot of us we
don't have PMs. We're not cursor but we
don't have PMs at at continue. Um but we
we like to push uh like engineers to
think like product engineers because you
know do more with less. Cool. Uh so I'm
winding down the plane or sort of
getting at the last stop of this train.
Um at continue we believe in amplified
dev. So, it's not about replacing
developers, it's about amplifying them.
Uh, so we don't have time for questions,
but I would love to talk to you in the
side or at lunch. Um, and again, for
whatever reason, I'm going to dox myself
and say that's where I'm staying. Um,
and, uh, in Brooklyn, uh, find me on
Buggy. Uh, Google me. Thank you.
[applause]
Heat. Heat.
[music]